<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rajdeep Chatterjee</title>
    <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rajdeep Chatterjee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Science Interview Questions - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_3/</guid>
      <description>Question 1 - What are Eigenvectors and Eigenvalues? A matrix represents a linear transformation. When a vector is multiplied to a matrix, it is similar to applying a transformation to the vector, and the result is the transformed vector. If, after the transformation, the vector stays in its span, then it is called an eigenvector.
But, due to the transformation, the vector may be stretched or squished. The amount by which it gets stretched or squished is called the eigenvalue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Science Interview Questions - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_2/</guid>
      <description>Question 1 - Can you explain the difference between a Validation Set and a Test Set? What is a good model in machine learning? A model is good if it can generalize on the unseen data. When a model is trained on some data, the model is expected to perform well on that data. But in use, the model has to predict on unknown data. If a model fails to generalize, then the predictions of the model may not be of much use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/random-forest/</guid>
      <description>Random Forest Decision Tree algorithm work great with the data that is used to create them. They are easy to build and interpret. But, they are not flexible when it comes to classifying new samples. Decision Trees tend to overfit.
Random Forest is also a tree based algorithm but it is more flexible. It is also called ensamble as it represents a group of decision trees working together as a single classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Science Interview Questions - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/exploring_ds_interview_q_1/</guid>
      <description>Question 1 Generate a fair coin from a biased one If there is a biased coin, it means that the probability of H and T are not equal. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that the probability for H is p. That of T would be q = (1-p).
If we flip the biased coin 2 times, then following are the possibilities and their corresponding probabilities:
        P(HH) = p2   P(HT) = pq   P(TH) = qp   P(TT) = q2    We notice that the P(HT) and P(TH) are same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population and Sample</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/population-and-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/population-and-sample/</guid>
      <description>Population and Sample What is a population? Population is the group of things that we want information about. For example, Suppose we want to know if children below 10 years prefer to play board games or mobile games these days. Then all children below 10 years become our population.
But we can not identify or examine every children below 10 years, as it is costly, time consuming and often practically impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Lie with Statistics by Darell Huff - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/how-to-lie-with-statistics-book-discussion-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/how-to-lie-with-statistics-book-discussion-introduction/</guid>
      <description>How to Lie with Statistics is a book by Darell Huff. First published in 1954, this book presents a very easy-going approach to rationally interpret and question the numbers that are advertised everywhere. With plenty of real-life examples, the author highlights how the marketing campaigns use some statistical statements to influence the mass, without any solid grounds to justify the same.
I find it often hard to relate technical terms used in regular text books, to real-life scenerios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the Seattle Rain Problem using Bayes&#39; Theorem</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/seattle_rain_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/blog/seattle_rain_prob/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Statement  You are about to get on a plane to Seattle. You want to know if you should bring an umbrella.
You call 3 random friends of yours who live there and ask each independently if it’s raining. Each of your friends has a 2/3 chance of telling you the truth and a 1/3 chance of messing with you by lying. All 3 friends tell you that “Yes” it is raining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Portfolio Website</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/portfolio/hugo-portfolio-website-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/portfolio/hugo-portfolio-website-copy/</guid>
      <description>I created my portfolio website using Hugo and UIKit, it serves as an online resume containing all my work.
This has been created as a theme so that others can use and adapt it.
Sections Homepage The homepage provides the basic information about you, including links to social media, skills you have, things you&amp;rsquo;ve done and your education. This page makes good use of UIKit grid and cards for organising all the information and ensuring it is responsive to work on mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Portfolio Website</title>
      <link>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/portfolio/hugo-portfolio-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chatterjeerajdeep.github.io/portfolio/hugo-portfolio-website/</guid>
      <description>I created my portfolio website using Hugo and UIKit, it serves as an online resume containing all my work.
This has been created as a theme so that others can use and adapt it.
Sections Homepage The homepage provides the basic information about you, including links to social media, skills you have, things you&amp;rsquo;ve done and your education. This page makes good use of UIKit grid and cards for organising all the information and ensuring it is responsive to work on mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>